<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">Clausura</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Einstellungen</string>
    <string name="title_activity_detail">Details</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit_exam" translatable="false">EditExamActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_create_or_edit" translatable="false">CreateOrEditActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_exam_details" translatable="false">ExamDetailsActivity</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_exam_edit">Bearbeiten</string>
    <string name="title_activity_backup_restore">Datensicherung</string>
    <string name="button_backup">Sichern</string>
    <string name="button_restore">Wiederherstellen</string>
    <string name="text_backup_info">"Hier kannst Du eine Sicherungskopie aller Termine"
        "anlegen.\n\nDie Daten werden im Ordner \n\"Documents\\Clausura\" gespeichert. \nVon dort"
        "aus kannst Du sie z.B. auf ein anderes Gerät kopieren. \n\nDafür"
        "muss Clausura auf Deinen Speicher zugreifen dürfen!"
    </string>
    <string name="text_permission_denied_restore">Keine Berechtigung gewährt. Wiederherstellen fehlgeschlagen.</string>
    <string name="text_permission_denied_backup">Keine Berechtigung gewährt. Backup fehlgeschlagen.</string>
    <string name="dialog_backup_success">Daten erfolgreich gesichert!</string>
    <string name="dialog_backup_fail_permission">Sicherung der Daten fehlgeschlagen, da kein Speicherzugriff gewährt wurde!</string>
    <string name="dialog_restore_success">Daten erfolgreich wiederhergestellt!</string>
    <string name="dialog_restore_fail_permission">Wiederherstellung der Daten fehlgeschlagen, da kein Speicherzugriff gewährt wurde!</string>
    <string name="dialog_backup_fail_other">Sicherung der Daten fehlgeschlagen!</string>
    <string name="dialog_restore_fail_other">Wiederherstellung der Daten fehlgeschlagen!</string>
    <string name="button_cancel">Abbrechen</string>
    <string name="title_choose_backup">Sicherung auswählen</string>
    <string name="dialog_restore_fail_no_backups">Es sind noch keine Sicherungen vorhanden!</string>
    <string name="text_backup_from">Sicherung vom</string>
    <string name="text_backup_file_prefix">Clausura Sicherung</string>
    <string name="hint_title">Titel</string>
    <string name="hint_date">Datum</string>
    <string name="hint_time">Uhrzeit</string>
    <string name="hint_location">Ort hinzufügen</string>
    <string name="hint_notes">Notiz hinzufügen</string>
    <string name="button_delete">Entfernen</string>
    <string name="button_edit">Bearbeiten</string>
    <string name="text_end_of_lecture">Ende der Vorlesungszeit</string>
    <string name="text_tomorrow">Morgen</string>
    <string name="text_today">Heute</string>
    <string name="text_yesterday">Gestern</string>
    <string name="text_x_days_ago">Vor %1$d Tagen</string>
    <string name="text_in_x_days">In %1$d Tagen</string>
    <string name="text_copyright">© 2016 Nico Assfalg</string>
    <string name="button_update">Update suchen</string>
    <string name="button_close">Schließen</string>
    <string name="button_license">Lizenz</string>
    <string name="text_license">MIT License\n\n
Copyright © 2017 Nico Aßfalg\n\n
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:\n\n
The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all
copies or substantial portions of the Software.\n\n
THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE
SOFTWARE.
</string>
    <string name="text_about_headline">Info</string>
    <string name="shortcut_add_short">Neue Klausur</string>
    <string name="shortcut_add_long">Eine neue Klausur hinzufügen</string>
    <string name="shortcut_add_disabled">Hinzufügen nicht möglich!</string>
    <string name="text_logo_credit">Logo von Niklas Braun</string>
    <string name="text_no_exams">Willkommen bei Clausura. \nTrage jetzt deine erste Klausur ein!</string>
    <string name="text_no_exams_past">Keine Klausuren zum Anzeigen vorhanden.</string>
    <string name="button_show_past_plural">%1$d vergangene Termine zeigen</string>
    <string name="button_show_past_singular">Vergangenen Termin zeigen</string>
    <string name="text_update_available">Update verfügbar!</string>
    <string name="button_download">Herunterladen</string>
    <string name="text_version">Version</string>
    <string name="title_activity_settings">Einstellungen</string>
    <string name="text_settings_head_ui">Darstellung</string>
    <string name="text_show_past">Vergangene Termine anzeigen</string>
    <string name="text_show_pinned">Hervorgehobener Termin</string>
    <string name="text_show_pinned_description">wird immer oben angezeigt</string>
    <string name="text_pinned_title">Titel des hervorgehobenen Termins</string>
    <string name="text_about_clausura">Über Clausura…</string>
    <string name="text_pinned_date">Datum des hervorgehobenen Termins</string>
    <string name="button_save">Speichern</string>
    <string name="text_error_empty">Ende der Vorlesungszeit</string>
    <string name="text_about_joda">Über Joda-Time…</string>
    <string name="text_license_joda" tools:ignore="TypographyOther">
        Apache License\n
        Version 2.0, January 2004\n
        http://www.apache.org/licenses/\n
    \n
        TERMS AND CONDITIONS FOR USE, REPRODUCTION, AND DISTRIBUTION\n
\n
   1. Definitions.\n\n

      "License" shall mean the terms and conditions for use, reproduction,\n
      and distribution as defined by Sections 1 through 9 of this document.\n\n

      "Licensor" shall mean the copyright owner or entity authorized by\n
      the copyright owner that is granting the License.\n\n

      "Legal Entity" shall mean the union of the acting entity and all\n
      other entities that control, are controlled by, or are under common\n
      control with that entity. For the purposes of this definition,\n
      "control" means (i) the power, direct or indirect, to cause the\n
      direction or management of such entity, whether by contract or\n
      otherwise, or (ii) ownership of fifty percent (50%) or more of the\n
      outstanding shares, or (iii) beneficial ownership of such entity.\n\n

      "You" (or "Your") shall mean an individual or Legal Entity\n
      exercising permissions granted by this License.\n\n

      "Source" form shall mean the preferred form for making modifications,\n
      including but not limited to software source code, documentation\n
      source, and configuration files.\n\n

      "Object" form shall mean any form resulting from mechanical\n
      transformation or translation of a Source form, including but\n
      not limited to compiled object code, generated documentation,\n
      and conversions to other media types.\n\n

      "Work" shall mean the work of authorship, whether in Source or\n
      Object form, made available under the License, as indicated by a\n
      copyright notice that is included in or attached to the work\n
      (an example is provided in the Appendix below).\n\n

      "Derivative Works" shall mean any work, whether in Source or Object\n
      form, that is based on (or derived from) the Work and for which the\n
      editorial revisions, annotations, elaborations, or other modifications\n
      represent, as a whole, an original work of authorship. For the purposes\n
      of this License, Derivative Works shall not include works that remain\n
      separable from, or merely link (or bind by name) to the interfaces of,\n
      the Work and Derivative Works thereof.\n\n

      "Contribution" shall mean any work of authorship, including\n
      the original version of the Work and any modifications or additions\n
      to that Work or Derivative Works thereof, that is intentionally\n
      submitted to Licensor for inclusion in the Work by the copyright owner\n
      or by an individual or Legal Entity authorized to submit on behalf of\n
      the copyright owner. For the purposes of this definition, "submitted"\n
      means any form of electronic, verbal, or written communication sent\n
      to the Licensor or its representatives, including but not limited to\n
      communication on electronic mailing lists, source code control systems,\n
      and issue tracking systems that are managed by, or on behalf of, the\n
      Licensor for the purpose of discussing and improving the Work, but\n
      excluding communication that is conspicuously marked or otherwise\n
      designated in writing by the copyright owner as "Not a Contribution."\n\n

      "Contributor" shall mean Licensor and any individual or Legal Entity\n
      on behalf of whom a Contribution has been received by Licensor and\n
      subsequently incorporated within the Work.\n\n

   2. Grant of Copyright License. Subject to the terms and conditions of\n
      this License, each Contributor hereby grants to You a perpetual,\n
      worldwide, non-exclusive, no-charge, royalty-free, irrevocable\n
      copyright license to reproduce, prepare Derivative Works of,\n
      publicly display, publicly perform, sublicense, and distribute the\n
      Work and such Derivative Works in Source or Object form.\n\n

   3. Grant of Patent License. Subject to the terms and conditions of\n
      this License, each Contributor hereby grants to You a perpetual,\n
      worldwide, non-exclusive, no-charge, royalty-free, irrevocable\n
      (except as stated in this section) patent license to make, have made,\n
      use, offer to sell, sell, import, and otherwise transfer the Work,\n
      where such license applies only to those patent claims licensable\n
      by such Contributor that are necessarily infringed by their\n
      Contribution(s) alone or by combination of their Contribution(s)\n
      with the Work to which such Contribution(s) was submitted. If You\n
      institute patent litigation against any entity (including a\n
      cross-claim or counterclaim in a lawsuit) alleging that the Work\n
      or a Contribution incorporated within the Work constitutes direct\n
      or contributory patent infringement, then any patent licenses\n
      granted to You under this License for that Work shall terminate\n
      as of the date such litigation is filed.\n\n

   4. Redistribution. You may reproduce and distribute copies of the\n
      Work or Derivative Works thereof in any medium, with or without\n
      modifications, and in Source or Object form, provided that You\n
      meet the following conditions:\n\n

      (a) You must give any other recipients of the Work or\n
          Derivative Works a copy of this License; and\n\n

      (b) You must cause any modified files to carry prominent notices\n
          stating that You changed the files; and\n\n

      (c) You must retain, in the Source form of any Derivative Works\n
          that You distribute, all copyright, patent, trademark, and\n
          attribution notices from the Source form of the Work,\n
          excluding those notices that do not pertain to any part of\n
          the Derivative Works; and\n\n

      (d) If the Work includes a "NOTICE" text file as part of its\n
          distribution, then any Derivative Works that You distribute must\n
          include a readable copy of the attribution notices contained\n
          within such NOTICE file, excluding those notices that do not\n
          pertain to any part of the Derivative Works, in at least one\n
          of the following places: within a NOTICE text file distributed\n
          as part of the Derivative Works; within the Source form or\n
          documentation, if provided along with the Derivative Works; or,\n
          within a display generated by the Derivative Works, if and\n
          wherever such third-party notices normally appear. The contents\n
          of the NOTICE file are for informational purposes only and\n
          do not modify the License. You may add Your own attribution\n
          notices within Derivative Works that You distribute, alongside\n
          or as an addendum to the NOTICE text from the Work, provided\n
          that such additional attribution notices cannot be construed\n
          as modifying the License.\n\n

      You may add Your own copyright statement to Your modifications and\n
      may provide additional or different license terms and conditions\n
      for use, reproduction, or distribution of Your modifications, or\n
      for any such Derivative Works as a whole, provided Your use,\n
      reproduction, and distribution of the Work otherwise complies with\n
      the conditions stated in this License.\n\n

   5. Submission of Contributions. Unless You explicitly state otherwise,\n
      any Contribution intentionally submitted for inclusion in the Work\n
      by You to the Licensor shall be under the terms and conditions of\n
      this License, without any additional terms or conditions.\n
      Notwithstanding the above, nothing herein shall supersede or modify\n
      the terms of any separate license agreement you may have executed\n
      with Licensor regarding such Contributions.\n\n

   6. Trademarks. This License does not grant permission to use the trade\n
      names, trademarks, service marks, or product names of the Licensor,\n
      except as required for reasonable and customary use in describing the\n
      origin of the Work and reproducing the content of the NOTICE file.\n\n

   7. Disclaimer of Warranty. Unless required by applicable law or\n
      agreed to in writing, Licensor provides the Work (and each\n
      Contributor provides its Contributions) on an "AS IS" BASIS,\n
      WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or\n
      implied, including, without limitation, any warranties or conditions\n
      of TITLE, NON-INFRINGEMENT, MERCHANTABILITY, or FITNESS FOR A\n
      PARTICULAR PURPOSE. You are solely responsible for determining the\n
      appropriateness of using or redistributing the Work and assume any\n
      risks associated with Your exercise of permissions under this License.\n\n

   8. Limitation of Liability. In no event and under no legal theory,\n
      whether in tort (including negligence), contract, or otherwise,\n
      unless required by applicable law (such as deliberate and grossly\n
      negligent acts) or agreed to in writing, shall any Contributor be\n
      liable to You for damages, including any direct, indirect, special,\n
      incidental, or consequential damages of any character arising as a\n
      result of this License or out of the use or inability to use the\n
      Work (including but not limited to damages for loss of goodwill,\n
      work stoppage, computer failure or malfunction, or any and all\n
      other commercial damages or losses), even if such Contributor\n
      has been advised of the possibility of such damages.\n\n

   9. Accepting Warranty or Additional Liability. While redistributing\n
      the Work or Derivative Works thereof, You may choose to offer,\n
      and charge a fee for, acceptance of support, warranty, indemnity,\n
      or other liability obligations and/or rights consistent with this\n
      License. However, in accepting such obligations, You may act only\n
      on Your own behalf and on Your sole responsibility, not on behalf\n
      of any other Contributor, and only if You agree to indemnify,\n
      defend, and hold each Contributor harmless for any liability\n
      incurred by, or claims asserted against, such Contributor by reason\n
      of your accepting any such warranty or additional liability.\n\n

   END OF TERMS AND CONDITIONS
    </string>
    <string name="text_joda_version">Joda-Time 2.9.9</string>
    <string name="text_joda_link">
        http://www.joda.org/joda-time/index.html
    </string>
    <string name="text_updates">Updates</string>
    <string name="text_only_wifi">Nur WLAN</string>
    <string name="text_only_wifi_explanation">Updates werden nur via WLAN gesucht</string>
    <string name="text_only_wifi_explanation_false">Updates werden immer gesucht</string>

    <string name="text_backup_warning">In aktuelleren Android-Versionen kann es Probleme beim Wiederherstellen geben!</string>
</resources>
